Guide to the Raymond C. Battalio and John B. Van Huyck Papers, 1949-2014, bulk 1972-2014 RL.11714
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1972-2014; 1
  - Articles and Book Chapters, 1972-2014; 1
    - Commitment versus Discretion in the Peasant-Dictator Game, undated (Box 10)
      Diagram proofs for publication.
    - Comment on J. J. Siegfried's "The Publishing of Economic Papers and its Impact on Graduate Faculty Ratings, 1960-1969", 1973 (Box 10)
    - Comment on P. Byron's "The Restricted Aitken Estimation of Sets of Demand Relations", 1973 (Box 10)
    - Commodity-Choice Behavior with Pigeons as Subjects, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Conditional Beliefs and Learning in Stag Hunt Games, 1994-2002; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Consumer Demand Theory Applied to Choice Behavior of Rats, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Consumption-Leisure Trade-Offs in Pigeons, 1987 (Box 10)
    - Consumption-Leisure Trade-Offs of Animal Workers, 1985 (Box 10)
    - Control Islip Token Economy Experiment I, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Coordination Failure in Market Statistic Games, 1998 (Box 10)
    - Decentralized Competition, Pecuniary Externalities, and Allocative Efficiency, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Demand Curves for Animal Consumers, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Do Learning Models Provide Effective Prescriptions, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Do Sunk Costs Matter, undated (Box 10)
    - Dynamic Monetary Control and Intermediate Targeting, 1987 (Box 10)
    - Economic Demand Theory and Psychological Studies of Choice, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Economic Perspectives in Behaviour Therapy, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Effects of Cannabis and Negotiated Wage Rate Changes on Income and Job Performance in an Experimental Token Economy, undated (Box 10)
      Copy.
    - Effects of Monetary Rebates, Feedback, and Information on Residential Electricity Conservation, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Equity, Efficiency, and Security in Tacit Bargaining Games, 1988 and undated; 5 folders (Box 10)
    - Eureka Learning, 2013 (Box 11)
    - Evidence on Learning in Coordination Games, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Experimental Confirmation of the Existence of a Giffen Good, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Experimental Studies of Consumer Demand Behavior Using Laboratory Animals, 1975 (Box 11)
    - First-Price Common Value Auctions, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Handbook of Experimental Economics Results--Plott/Smith, 1995-2001 (Box 11)
      Draft chapter and correspondence.
    - History's Role in Coordinating Decentralized Allocation Decisions, 1988-1992; 5 folders (Box 11)
      Drafts, notes, research material, and referee-related correspondence.
    - Implications for Concepts of Psychopathology of Studies of Economic Principles in Behavior Therapy Programs, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Income Distributions in Two Experimental Economies, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Income-Leisure Trade-Offs of Animal Workers, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Is Reputation a Substitute for Commitment in the Peasant-Dictator Game, 1996; 6 folders (Box 11)
      Copy and research material.
    - Job Choice and Total Labor Supply, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Labor Supply Behavior of Animal Workers, 1979 (Box 11)
    - Learning Conditional Behavior in Similar Stag Hunt Games, 2002 (Box 11)
    - Lucas Critique, Rational Expectations, and the Theory of Economic Policy, 1983; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Marihuana and Work Performance, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Matching versus Maximizing, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Maximization Theory in Behavioral Psychology, 1987 (Box 11)
    - Monetary Standard Switching, Reputation, and Rational Policy Making, undated (Box 11)
    - Myopia, Foresight, and Policy Discretion in the Optimal Seigniorage Problem, 1984 (Box 11)
    - On the Origin of Convention (1-2 of 7), 1990 and undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
      Research material.
    - On the Origin of Convention (3-7 of 7), 1990-1992 and undated; 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Optimal Prices and Animal Consumers in Congested Markets, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Output Change Under Third Degree Discrimination, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Rational Expectations Policy Analysis: A Critique, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Residential Electricity Demand: An Experimental Study, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Risk Aversion in Rats Under Varying Levels of Resource Availability, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Seigniorage, Sovereign Debt, and Reputation, 1986; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Selection Dynamics, Asymptotic Stability, and Adaptive Behavior, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Some Evidence of a Monetary Business Cycle, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Strategic Uncertainty, Focal Principles, and Coordination Failure in Average Opinion Games, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Substitutability in Time Allocation, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Sunk and Opportunity Costs in Valuation and Bidding, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Tacit Coordination Games, Strategic Uncertainty, and Coordination Failure, 1988-1989 and undated; 3 folders (Box 12)
      Copy, drafts, research material, and correspondence.
    - Testing Between Alternative Models of Choice Under Uncertainty, 1981 (Box 12)
      Reprint and draft.
    - Testing Between Non-Expected Utility Theories, 1986-1988; 2 folders (Box 12)
      Draft, notes, and correspondence.
    - Tests of Competing Theories of Consumer Choice and the Representative Consumer Hypothesis, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Tests of "Fanning Out" of Indifference Curves, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Tests of Rational Expectations in a Stark Setting, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Test of Some Alternative Theories of Individual Choice Behavior, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Token Economy and Animal Models for the Experimental Analysis of Economic Behavior, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Two-Part Tariff and Monopoly Profits When Costs are Variable, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Untitled Paper, undated (Box 12)
      Untitled draft on money and inflation.
    - Volunteer Artifacts in Experiments in Economics, 1979 (Box 12)
      Reprint and copy.
    - What Does It Take to Eliminate the Use of a Strategy Dominated by a Mixture Electronic Files, 1994; 47 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0004, Box 66, Disk RL11714-FL3-0002)
  - Referee Reports, 1992-2008
    Van Huyck's referee reports and related correspondence with journal editors. Arranged alphabetically by author's last name (Van Huyck also added subject or short title).
    - Abbink et al., Adaptive, 2006 (Box 13)
    - American Economic Review, Are Two Heads Better Than One, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Anderhub, Long-term Work Contracts, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Anderson, Bank Run Experiment, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Andreoni et al., Fairness, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Bagnoli and Watts, Product Quality Choice, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Bornstein et al., Coordination, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Burninghaus and Ehrhart, Economic Letters, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Burton and Sefton, Risk, Pre-Play Communication, and Equilibrium, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Charness, Attribution, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Charness and Gooskopf, Cheap Talk, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Charness and Harvey, Altruism, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Cooper and Kagel, Context, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Cox et al., Bayesian, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Cox et al., Bayesian Electronic Files, 1994-1996; 16 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0004, Box 72, Disk RL11714-FL3-0745)
    - Gaschter and Falk, Reputation or Reciprocity, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Hauk, Discriminating, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Hauk et al., To Commit, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Hauk, Multiple Prisoner's Dilemma, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Hauk, Strategic Delegation, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Hoffman et al., Prompting Strategic Reasoning, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Hays and Richards, Short-Term Learning, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Kirkchamp and Nagel, Local and Group Interaction, 2001; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Kritikos and Bolle, Punishment as a Public Good, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Leady, Learning and Imitation, 2002 (Box 13)
    - Noussair and Faith, Mixed Strategy Play, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Oakenfels and Bolton, A Stress Test, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Rapoport et al., Coordination, 2000; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Referee Reports Electronic Files, 1992-2008; 584 files; approximately 145 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0004)
      Text and image files.
    - Schmidt, Playing Safe, 1998; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Schotter and Sopher, Social Learning, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Sefton, Coordination Games, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Shachat, Mixed Strategy, 1996 (Box 13)
    - Shachat, Mixed Strategy Electronic Files, 1993-1996; 17 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0004, Box 72, Disk RL11714-FL3-0746)
    - Shor, Learning to Respond, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Slonim and Leider, Does Experience Always Pay, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Stahl, Equilibrium Selection, undated (Box 13)
    - Sterbenz and Phillips, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Tang, Anticipatory Learning, 1997; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Valley et al., Dyadic, undated (Box 13)
    - Valley, How Communication, undated (Box 13)
    - Weber, Uncommon Knowledge, 1999 (Box 14)
    - Zwick and Rapoport, Tacit Coordination, 2000 (Box 14)
  - Special Issue of Experimental Economics in Honor of Battalio, 2006
    Includes correspondence and submitted papers; Van Huyck co-edited.
    - Blume, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Capra, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Cason, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Charness, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Chong, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Crawford, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Croson, 2006 (Box 14)
    - DeJong, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Duffy, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Eckel, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Fatas, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Gneezy, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Harvey, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Heal, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Hess/Holt, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Knez, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Monderer, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Nagel, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Ortmann, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Referee Requests, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Schotter, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Stahl, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Sefton, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Sopher, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Van Huyck, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Weber, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Wilcox, 2006 (Box 14)
- Research, 1949-2014
  Material such as research files, grant proposals, and writings by others that Battalio and Van Huyck kept for reference. The largest files are on the Advanced Research Program (ARP), equilibrium selection, National Science Foundation (NSF), and soverign debt. Organized into two subseries: Research and Notes and Writings by Others.
  - Research and Notes, 1975-2014
    Includes notes, plans, proposals, reports, and supporting material. The largest files are on the Advanced Research Program (ARP), equilibrium selection, National Science Foundation (NSF), and soverign debt. Arranged alphabetically by subject or oganization.
    - A Theoretical and Empirical Examination of the Impact of Futures Markets on the Performance of Spot Markets for Texas Agricultural Products, 1991 (Box 29)
      Funding proposal and supporting material.
    - Advanced Research Program (ARP), 1987-2001; 11 folders (Box 29)
      Funding proposals submitted to the Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board.
    - Artificial Intelligence, Strategic Rationality, and Human Behavior, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 29)
      Funding proposals.
    - Aspen Proposal, 1991 (Box 30)
    - Asymmetric Information in Output Coordination, 1987-1988 (Box 30)
      Proposal to the Center for Energy and Mineral Resources at TAMU.
    - Auction Theory: Non-Expected Utility and Strategic Uncertainty, 1993 (Box 30)
    - Battalio Invoices, 1991 (Box 30)
      Equipment invoices.
    - Battalio Research Notes, 1991 (Box 30)
      Unlabeled research notes.
    - Budget, 1992-1994; 2 folders (Box 30)
      For various proposals and projects.
    - Business Cycle Bibliography, 1984 (Box 33)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1988 (Box 30)
      Letter inquiring about Van Huyck's interest in potential fellowship.
    - Center for Energy and Mineral Resources, 1988 (Box 30)
      List of proposal ideas.
    - Citation Index, 1995 (Box 33)
      Printout of directory of citations.
    - Computer Directory Printouts, undated (Box 64)
      Printouts of file trees.
    - Computer Manuals, 1998 (Box 33)
    - Daily Notes, 2006 (Box 33)
    - Dell Technical Instructions, 1998 (Box 33)
      Repair instructions.
    - Designing Computer Assisted Auctions, 1999 (Box 30)
      Funding proposal.
    - Discretion, Interest Rates, and Stabilization Policy, 1986 (Box 33)
      Notes on conversation with Tabellini.
    - Discretionary Policy, Intermediate Targets, and Federal Reserve Operating Procedures, 1986 (Box 33)
      Notes.
    - Economic Growth, Political Institutions, and Expropriation, 1987 (Box 33)
    - Endogenous Policy Objectives, 1982 (Box 33)
      Notes and draft proposal.
    - Equilibrium Selection (1-12 of 16), 1988-1996; 12 folders (Box 30)
      Funding proposals to multiple entities, grant renewals, reporting, and expense tracking.
    - Equilibrium Selection (13-16 of 16), 1989-2014; 4 folders (Box 33)
    - Federal Highway Administration (FHWA), Department of Transportation, 2009 (Box 30)
      Proposal material.
    - Freedom of Information Act: Secrecy in a Democracy, 1988 (Box 33)
      Research plan.
    - Funded Proposals, 1989-1997; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Futures Market, 1989 (Box 31)
      Funding proposal submitted to the Texas Higher Education Board.
    - Gold Clauses, 1986 (Box 33)
    - Grant Log Sheets, 1989-1991; 3 folders (Box 31)
      Expense tracking.
    - Humanities and Social Science Enhancement of Research Capacity (HASS ERC) Grant Proposal, undated (Box 31)
      Notes for potential internal grant proposal.
    - History as a Coordination Mechanism in a Competitive Market, 1991-1995; 5 folders (Box 31)
      Grant proposals, reporting, and expense tracking.
    - Hyperinflation, 1986-1987; undated; 4 folders (Box 33)
      Notes and research plans.
    - IBM Technology Transfer, 1999 (Box 31)
      Software license.
    - Ideas, 1985-1989 (Box 33)
      Notes on research ideas.
    - Institutional Responses to the Sovereignty Problem, 1986 (Box 33)
      Outline.
    - Institutional Review Board (IRB) Approvals, 2009-2012; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - IRB Forms, 2013 (Box 33)
      Sample approval and consent forms.
    - Interdisciplinary Research Initiative Award, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 31)
      Funding proposal to TAMU.
    - International Enhancement Grants, 1987-1988 (Box 31)
      Calls for proposals for internal grants at TAMU.
    - Lab Equipment, 1994-2001; 8 folders (Box 31)
      Invoices and correspondence on computer equipment for ERL.
    - Learning to Play Nash in Public Goods Environments, 1993-1997; 4 folders (Box 31)
    - Limitations on Government Borrowing, Budget Deficits, and Hyperinflation, 1987 (Box 31)
    - Looting America: The Profession of "Legal Entrepreneurs", 1989 (Box 33)
      Newspaper and magazine clippings.
    - Mathematica Plus Program, 1993 (Box 64)
    - Maximal Seigniorage under Imperfect Monetary Control, 1987 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous Computer Notes, 2006 (Box 33)
      Notes on ERL.
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 33)
    - Modelling Economic Policy: Rational Policy Process, 1984 (Box 33)
    - Monetary Standard Switching, 1984-1985; 4 folders (Box 33)
    - Money, 1982 (Box 33)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), 1988 (Box 31)
      Grant program material.
    - National Science Foundation (NSF), 1994-2000; 3 folders (Box 31)
      Final reports on funded research.
    - NSF: Center for Decision Making Under Uncertainty, 2003 (Box 32)
      Notes on proposal.
    - NSF: Consumer Demand, 1978 (Box 32)
      Grant proposal and supporting material.
    - NSF: Coordination, 1997; 3 folders (Box 32)
      Grant proposals and expense tracking.
    - NSF: Coordination Failure and Interdependent Beliefs in Experimental Keynesian Coordination Games, 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - NSF: Coordination Success, 2004 (Box 32)
    - NSF: Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship (IGERT), 2001-2004; 2 folders (Box 32)
      Outline of grant requirements and notes on grant proposal.
    - NSF: Interpretation Systems for Empirical Economic Theories, 1975-1976 (Box 32)
      Research agreement.
    - NSF: Learning Equilibrium Behavior, 1994-1997; 4 folders (Box 32)
      Grant proposal, supporting material, reporting, and expense tracking.
    - NSF: New Computing Environment, 2000 (Box 32)
      Grant proposal for "Acquisition and Development of a New Computing Environment" for the Department of Economics.
    - NSF: Reputation, 1986 (Box 32)
      Grant proposal that Van Huyck contributed to for project on "Reputational Models of Economic Policy," submitted by Herschel Grossman and NBER.
    - NSF: Strategic Behavior, Dynamical Systems, and Equilibrium Selection, 1991-1995; 3 folders (Box 32)
    - NSF: Strategic Uncertainty, Focal Principles, and Coordination Failure, 1988; 2 folders (Box 32)
      Grant proposal.
    - NSF: Three by Three Game, 2003; 4 folders (Box 32)
      Draft grant proposals and supporting material.
    - Notes on Dissertation, 1984 and undated; 2 folders (Box 33)
      Notes on advising conversations.
    - Pecuniary Externalities and Inefficient Cross-Hauling, 1989 (Box 33)
    - Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle (PHEV) Proposal, 2009; undated; 2 folders (Box 32)
      Grant proposal and supporting material for Texas Transportation Institute.
    - Private Information and Monetary Reform, 1986 (Box 33)
    - Processed Daily Notes, 2006 (Box 33)
      Handwritten notes on daily research activities.
    - Public Expenditures and Business Cycles: Empirical Evidence, 1985-1986 (Box 33)
    - Public Goods, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 32)
      Notes and material for potential proposals.
    - Public Goods and Real Business Cycles, 1985-2002; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Research Agenda, 2004 (Box 33)
      Printout of working notes document.
    - Research Electronic Files, 1991-2005; 18,009 files; approximately 2.1 gigabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0005)
      Text, image, executable, dataset, spreadsheet, audio, and backup files; zipped folders.
    - Resources for the Future, 1987 (Box 33)
      Information on grants program.
    - SAGE Foundation, 1988 (Box 33)
      Correspondence on research proposal submitted to Russell Sage Foundation.
    - Statistical Analysis System (SAS), 1996 (Box 64)
    - School Reform, 1993-1997; 4 folders (Box 33)
      Readings and notes.
    - Sectoral Shocks and Aggregate Fluctuations, 1993; undated; 3 folders (Box 33)
    - Seigniorage and Real Tax Revenues, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1987 (Box 33)
      Correspondence about mailing list.
    - Social Health Insurance, Adverse Selection and Accidental Bequests, 1986 (Box 33)
    - Sovereign Debt, 1985-1987; 13 folders (Box 33)
    - Summer Research Award Program, 1986-1991 (Box 33)
      Research proposals for internal grants at TAMU.
    - Tax Code Ambiguity, 1987 (Box 34)
    - Telecommunications and Information Task Force, 2002 (Box 34)
      Request for proposals.
    - Testing the Seiniorage Model, undated (Box 34)
    - Use of Dutch and English Auctions to Solve Coordination Problems in Markets with Strategic Complementarities, 1995-1998; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Viewsonic, 2000 (Box 64)
      Information on computer monitors.
  - Writings by Others, 1949-2012
    Access note. Some materials are electronic records that require special equipment. Contact Research Services with questions. Arranged alphabetically.
    Of note is a file that contains Rolodex cards that Van Huyck used to index frequently referenced sources. Arranged alphabetically by first letter of lead author's last name or subject.
    - A, 1989-2008; 7 folders (Box 25)
    - Animal Press Releases, 1986 (Box 25)
      Articles on animal experimentation in laboratories.
    - B, 1983-2010; 24 folders (Box 25)
    - C (1-2 of 17), 1991-2008; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - C (3-17 of 17), 1984-2001; 15 folders (Box 26)
    - D, 1980-2010; 4 folders (Box 26)
    - Designing Auctions, 1991 (Box 26)
    - E, 1980-2004; 4 folders (Box 26)
    - F, 1971-2006; 15 folders (Box 26)
    - G, 1990-2010; 6 folders (Box 26)
    - H, 1982-2007; 11 folders (Box 26)
    - I, 1977; undated; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Index, undated; 3 folders (Box 27)
      Van Huyck's Rolodex cards of frequently referenced sources.
    - J, 1990-2005; 4 folders (Box 27)
    - K, 1983-2007; 7 folders (Box 27)
    - L, 1966-2008; 5 folders (Box 27)
    - Learning Algorithms, 1992-1993 (Box 27)
    - M, 1968-2004; 17 folders (Box 27)
    - N, 2003 (Box 27)
    - O, undated (Box 28)
    - P, 1980-1997; 12 folders (Box 28)
    - Prediction Markets, 1988-2006; 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Q, 1979-1988; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Quantal Response Equilibria, 1993 (Box 28)
    - R, 1979-2008; 16 folders (Box 28)
    - S, 1949-2005; 24 folders (Box 28)
    - Sovereignty and Growth, 1988 (Box 29)
    - T, 1973-2008; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - V, 1969-1989; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - W, 1981-2009; undated; 24 folders (Box 29)
    - Writings by Others Electronic Files, 1991-2012; 8,476 files; approximately 1.9 gigabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0005)
      Image, text, executable, and database files; zipped folder.
    - Y, 1977-1992; 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Z, 1983-2007; 4 folders (Box 29)
- Experiments, 1986-2013
  Access restricted. Some electronic files in RL11714-SET-0008 contain personally identifiable information (PII) that has not been redacted. Contact Research Services for more information.
  Material such as correspondence, experiment data (response sheets, tabulated responses, and printouts of data), statistical data analysis of results, participant instructions, and design notes for Battalio and Van Huyck's experiments on economic decision making and interactions. Data analysis was typically done with software, such as SAS, Stata, and Mathematica, and this series features a majority of the electronic records and audiovisual material.
  Battalio and Van Huyck coded their experiments to indicate type and vintage (some experiments were conducted multiple times, presumably with extensions and modifications), and these codes are used as file titles when possible. The most frequently used codes are as follows: BB are beauty contest games inspired by Keynes's example of the workings of financial markets; C or CONV followed by a number are experiments on conventions; CR or CRAW followed by a number are coordination games; DEC followed by a letter and/or number or DX followed by a number are on decentralized allocation decisions; and PD followed by a number are peasant-dictator games. Codes appearing in this series also appear in the Articles and Book Chapters subseries, possibly allowing connections to be made between published writings and experiment files.
  Organized into eight subseries: Average Opinion, Chaos, Conventions, Coordination, Decentralized Allocation, Peasant-Dictator, Other Experiments and Related Material, and Uncategorized Electronic Records.
  - Average Opinion Games, 1988-2006
    Files for experiments on asset markets, in which participants guess the average opinion of all participants involved. Arranged alphabetically by experiment.
    - Asset Market Games (PG), 1988 and undated; 13 folders (Box 34)
      Experiment design notes, participant instructions, response booklets, experiment data, and statistical analyses for price games.
    - Average Opinion Games (1-7 of 14), 1991-1997 and undated; 7 folders (Box 34)
      Experiment design notes, participant instructions, response booklets, experiment data, and statistical analyses.
    - Average Opinion Games (8-14 of 14), 1993-1994 and undated; 7 folders (Box 35)
    - Average Opinion Games Electronic Files, 2001-2003; 23 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0006, Box 71, Disk RL11714-FL3-0675, Box 77, Disk RL11714-FL5-0041)
      Image and text files; zipped folder.
    - Beauty Contest (BB1), 2001 and undated; 3 folders (Box 35)
      Experiment data and statistical analyses.